#### Contact

+923120372130 (Mobile) rashid.ali1604@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rashid-ali-1604 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

C#

.NET Core

ASP.NET

### Languages

Sindhi (Native or Bilingual)

Urdu (Full Professional)

English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

ASP.NET MVC 5 Essential Training
Using Generics in C#
Learning Entity Framework Core
Deploying ASP.NET Core
Applications

### Honors-Awards

PM's National ICT Scholarship Program

# Rashid Ali

Full Stack Developer | .Net Core | Asp.Net | Web API | Angular | React | Azure DevOps

Karāchi

## Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Back-End Web Development, ASP.NET,.NET CORE, and C#. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science - BS focused in Computer Science from National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences.

Working experience on Digital Bookshops, Process Automation and Digital Banking domains.

# Experience

TPS Worldwide Senior Software Engineer February 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Working with Delivery Channels Department responsible for providing customized Fintech services.

### Tasks/Responsibilities:

- Part of the team Backend team responsible for building APIs for Digital Banking apps ( Sokin )
- Integration with third party application Chargebee (Subscription Billing & Revenue Operation)
- Integration with payment gateway Checkout.com
- Integration with FIS (Credit/Debit Issuing)
- Building AWS Lambda functions

Arpatech (Pvt) Ltd (Pakistan Official)
Dotnet Developer
October 2020 - February 2021 (5 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Building APIs for Business Process Automation using Microservices Architecture.

Tools, Technologies, Patterns:

- .NET Core 3.1
- Swagger
- ASP.NET Web API
- Microservice Architecture
- API Gateway
- Azure DevOps
- SQL

Synergy-IT Pakistan
Junior Software Engineer
July 2018 - October 2020 (2 years 4 months)
Islamabad

Worked primarily as .NET Developer with a team dedicated for Danish customer Gyldendal.dk. A day involved communication with clients, designing and developing applications. Development included following best practices to build loosely coupled applications that are flexible to changes and scale-able based on micro-services architecture.

Tools, Technologies, Patterns:

- .NET Core 3.1
- ASP.NET Core 3.1
- ASP.NET Core Web API
- Swagger
- ASP.NET MVC Framework
- ASP.NET Web API
- SQL Server
- Entity Framework 6
- Entity Framework Core
- Azure DevOps
- Unit Tests
- JWT Token
- AutoMapper
- Redis Cache

Gyldendal Junior Software Engineer July 2018 - October 2020 (2 years 4 months) Denmark

Working in Team Extensions Model with Team of Gyldendal in Synergy-IT

# Education

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2014 - 2018)